{ Justin Clark }

Professional full stack developer dedicated to simplifying user experience and delivering beautiful websites. At the end of a two-year hiatus from the professional world of developing to finish an Associate's Degree in Programming, I'm now seeking another developer role where I can both be challenged, and make significant impacts in a collaborative environment.

EDUCATION

North Seattle College, Seattle, WA — Associates in Programming — GPA 3.60

JUNE 2018 – DECEMBER 2020

Seattle Vocational Institute, Seattle, WA — Office Certificate — GPA 3.98

JUNE 2004 - DECEMBER 2004

EXPERIENCE

Walt Disney, Seattle, WA — (All positions below)

Software Technical Specialist

AUGUST 2015 - JUNE 2018

- Co-developed an internal reporting dashboard application, with emphasis on the UI.
- Implemented an automated Continuous Delivery pipeline using git pushes.
- Managed QA on UI releases to production.
- Implemented SSO and enterprise-level security using SAML.
- Employed UI session storage in mongoDB allowing seamless live Node.js app restarts.
- Implemented application failover using Forever.js for UI server restarts.
- Implemented version control using git and GitLab.
- Created Bash scripts for analyzing codebase to reveal unused code.
- Regularly refactored UI and business logic improving maintainability & performance.
- Managed complete development lifecycle after Senior Dev and DB Engineer left team.
- Automated database updates using Task Manager, SSIS, PowerShell, and Excel.
- Persuaded management to allow rebuild of backend infrastructure.
- Created and maintained Confluence instance for site documentation.
- Developed new features to solve client business needs.
- Worked with business segment customers to resolve bug tickets.
- Implemented Jira Ticket creation directly in internal reporting website.

Business Operations Analyst

APRIL 2009 - AUGUST 2015

- Developed internal app using MS Access & VBA to organize reports.
- Converted MS Access app into an ASP.Net website using VB.
- Developed MS Access app for storing and processing vendor invoices.
- Enhanced reporting processes by finding and integrating efficiencies.
- Ensured continuity of service during multiple server migrations.
- Used VBA programming to automate reports in Excel spreadsheets.

Reporting Team Lead

JUNE 2007 - APRIL 2009

- Lead a team of four Third Party Reporting Analysts during a period of rapid growth.
- Streamlined processes allowing team to manage increasing workload & complexity.
- Developed reporting best practices resulting in faster turnaround of customer requests.
- Increased reporting efficiencies reducing the need to hire additional headcount.

Reporting Analyst

JANUARY 2007 - JUNE 2007

- Developed training materials used to on-board new team members.
- Broke down complex topics to convey information in an easy to understand manner.
- Responsible for data-entry of third-party advertising reporting data into spreadsheets.

Seattle, WA

Portfolio:

www.justinclark.dev

LinkedIn:

www.linkedin.com/in/justinclark-dev

FRONT END

- HTML5
- CSS3
- CSS Animations
- SASS
- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- Angular
- jQuery
- Bootstrap

BACK END

- Java
- Python
- Node.js
- ASP.NET (VB)
- VBA
- PHP

DATABASES

- SQL Server
- MySQL
- MongoDB

TOOLS

- NPM
- Grunt
- Git
- GitHub
- GitLab
- VS Code
- Jira
- Confluence

OS

- Linux Ubuntu Server
- Windows Server
- Windows
- MacOS